<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<entry>
<title type="html">GSoC project @Pitivi~Cut Mode</title>
<link href="https://unhired-coder.github.io/project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GSoC project @Pitivi~Cut Mode"/>
<content type="html">
  <main class="container">
        <article>
            <div class="row">
                <div class="col-lg-8 mx-auto" ;>
                    <h1 class="font-weight-bold mt-4">GSoC project @Pitivi~Cut Mode.</h1>
                </div>
            </div>
            <section class="mt-5">
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-lg-8 mx-auto">
                        <br>
                        <p>
                            The Idea for this project is to have two timelines to ease certain types
                            of tasks and increase productivity. This will essentially bring in a
                            non-zoomable Timeline which will serve to ease the task of trimming,
                            cutting, rearranging clips on the timeline in sync with the other
                            timeline.
                        </p>
                        <br>
                        <img class="col-lg-12" style="max-height: 300px;" src="https://unhired-coder.github.io/assets/images/priview_cut_mode_simple.png" style=" " alt="">
                    </div>
                </div>
                <br><br>
                <br><br>
                <br><br>
                <div class="row">
                    <div class="col-lg-8 mx-auto">
                        <h2 class="font-weight-bold">Benifits ?</h2>
                        <br>
                        <p>
                            Mostly, when we have a movie of a longer duration, we want to use the Zoom feature to see
                            the whole timeline and scroll in-out to perform edits and rearrange clips. It consumes a lot
                            of time which may be used productively somewhere, so to reduce user actions we have a zoom
                            fitted timeline with small height layers so that all the layers and tracks are always
                            visible. Now you only think about Zoom when you want to perform some precise edits, others
                            on the Zoom fitted timeline ;).
                        </p>
                        <br> <br>
                        From now, we will call the ZoomFitter timeline a <b>Mini Timeline</b> and the other simply a
                        <b>Timeline</b>.
                        <br> <br>
                        <h5>Longer duration timeline?</h5>
                        <p>You can easily keep track having the reduced size elements on the Mini Timeline.
                        </p>
                        <br><br>
                        <img class="col-lg-12" style="max-height: 300px;"  src="https://unhired-coder.github.io/assets/images/long_duration.gif" style=" " alt="">
                        <br> <br> <br> <br>
                        <h5>Many layers to work with?</h5>
                        <p>
                            Pitivi allows you to unlock all the views to a separate window, so If you have more layers,
                            you may undock the views to separate screens and expand the Mini Timeline to make all the
                            layers visible at the same time.</p>
                        <br>
                        <img class="col-lg-12" style="max-height: 300px;"  src="https://unhired-coder.github.io/assets/images/many_layers_to_work.png" style=" " alt="">
                        <br> <br> <br> <br>

                        <h5>Let's dive deep!</h5>
                        <br>
                        <p>
                            Consider a case where we want to edit a portion of a timeline, for
                            precise edits we have to zoom in at the required position, do the edits,
                            zoom out, move to the next position, and so on for subsequent edits.
                            This eats up a lot of precious time. The new global timeline allows the
                            user to see the zoomed view as well as keep track of position in the
                            global timeline at the same time. Now you can move anywhere in the
                            timeline with a single click, preserving the zoomed view.</p>
                        <br>
                        <img class="col-lg-12" style="max-height: 300px;" src="https://unhired-coder.github.io/assets/images/move_playhead.gif" style=" " alt="">
                        <br> <br> <br> <br>
                        <p>
                            Mini Timeline also allows you to rearrange clips so, where you have a short clip of
                            about a few seconds and you wish to relocate it, say from start to the end of the timeline,
                            you would select a clip, zoom out the timeline and drag it to end, zoom in to come to the
                            same state. Another way is to start dragging and use the over scroll mechanism and wait for
                            your desired position. Neither of them is ideal. The new global timeline allows to quickly
                            locate clips and drag them at any position since the entire duration is always in view.</p>
                        <br>
                        <img class="col-lg-12" style="max-height: 300px;"  src="https://unhired-coder.github.io/assets/images/move_clip.gif" style=" " alt="">
                        <br><br><br>
                        <p>
                            That's it for now. I will be adding more things here as they come.
                        </p>
                        <br>                        <p>
                            Half a month has passed, feeling great already.

                            <br><br>
                            Will update you soon, <br> Thanks!
                        </p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <br><br>
            </section>
        </article>
    </main>
</content>
<author>
<name>Pratyush Tiwari</name>
<email>pratyushtiwarimj@gmail.com</email>
</author>
<category term="pitivi"/>
<summary type="html">Pitivi-Cut Mode</summary>
</entry>
</feed>
